35 chapter 36 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 36 The Sunday
Cab One morning, as Jerry had just put me into the shafts and was fastening the
traces, a gentleman walked into the yard.
“Your servant, sir,” said Jerry good morning Mr. Barker,” said the gentleman. “I should be
glad to make some arrangements with you for taking Mrs. Briggs regularly to
church on Sunday mornings. We go to the New Church now, and that is rather
further than she can walk.” “Thank you, sir,” said Jerry, “but I have
only taken out a six days license,* and therefore I could not take air on a
Sunday; it would not be legal Oh!” said the other, “I did not know
yours was a six days cab; but of course it would be very easy to alter your
license. I would see that you did not lose by it; the fact is, Mrs. Briggs very
much prefers you to drive her.” “I should be glad to oblige the lady,
sir, but I had a 7 Days license once, and
the work was too hard for me, and too hard for my horses. Year in and year out,
not a day's rest, and never a Sunday with my wife and children; and never able to
go to a place of worship, which I had always been used to do before I took to
the driving box. So for the last 5 years I have only taken a six days license, and
I find it better all the way around Well, of course,” replied Mr. Briggs, “it is
very proper that every person should have rest, and be able to go to church on
Sundays, but I should have thought you would not have minded such a short
distance for the horse, and only once a day; you would have all the afternoon and
evening for yourself, and we are very good customers, you
know.” “Yes, sir, that is true, and I'm grateful for all favors, I am sure; and
anything that I could do to oblige you, or the lady, I should be proud and happy
to do; but I can't give up my Sundays, sir,
indeed I can't. I read that God made man, and he made horses and all the other
beasts, and as soon as He had made them
He made a day of rest, and B that all
should rest one day in seven; and I think, sir, He must have known what was good for
them, and I am sure it is good for me I'm stronger and healthier altogether, now
that I have a day of rest; the horses are
fresh too, and do not wear up nearly so fast. The Six Day drivers all tell me the
same, and I have laid by more money in the savings bank than ever I did before;
and as for the wife and children, sir, why, heart alive! they would not go back to
the seven days for all they could see.” “Oh, very well,” said the gentleman.
“Don't trouble yourself, Mr. Barker, any further. I will inquire somewhere else,” and he walked
away. “Well,” says Jerry to me, “we can't help it, Jack, old boy; we must have our
Sundays.” “Polly!” he shouted, “Polly! come here.” She was there in a
minute. “What is it all about, Jerry?” “Why, my dear, Mr. Briggs wants me to
take Mrs. Briggs to church every Sunday morning. I say I only have a six days
license. He says, 'Get a 7 Days license, and I'll make it worth your while;' and you
know, Polly, they are very good customers to us. Mrs. Briggs often goes out shopping
for hours, or making calls, and then she pays down fair and honorable like a lady;
there's no beating down or making 3 hours into 2 hours a half, as some folks
do; and it is easy work for the horses; not like tearing along to catch trains
for people that are always a quarter of an hour too late; and if I don't oblige
her in this matter it is very likely we shall lose them all together What do you
say, little woman?” “I say, Jerry,” says she, speaking very
slowly, “I say, if Mrs. Briggs would give you a sovereign every Sunday morning, I
would not have you a 7 days cabman again.
We have known what it was to have no Sundays, and now we know what it is to
call them our own. Thank God, you earn enough to keep us, though it is sometimes
close work to pay for all the oats and hay, the license, and the rent besides; but
Harry will soon be earning something, and I would rather struggle on harder than
we do than go back to those horrid times when you hardly had a minute to look at
your own children, and we never could go to a place of worship together, or have a
happy, quiet day. God forbid that we should ever turn back to those times; that's what I say,
Jerry.” “And that is just what I told Mr.
Briggs, my dear,” said Jerry, “and what I mean to stick to. So don't go and fret
yourself, Polly” (for she had begun to cry); “I would not go back to the old times if
I earned twice as much, so that is settled, little woman. Now, cheer up, and
I'll be off to the stand 3 weeks had passed away after this
conversation, and no order had come from Mrs. Briggs; so there was nothing but
taking jobs from the stand. Jerry took it to heart a great deal, for of course the
work was harder for horse and man. But Polly would always cheer him up, and say,
“Never mind, father, never, mind. “'Do your best, And leave the rest it will all come
right Some day or night.'” It soon became known that Jerry
had lost his best customer, and for what reason. Most of the men said he was a
fool, but two or three took his part. “If working men don't stick to their
Sunday,” said Truman, “they'll soon have none left; it is every man's right and
every beast's right. By God's law we have a day of rest, and by the law of England
we have a day of rest; and I say we ought
to hold the rights these laws give us and keep them for our
children.” “All very well for you religious chaps to talk so,” said Larry; “but I'll
turn a shilling when I can. I don't believe in religion, for I don't see that
your religious folks are any better than the rest.” “If they are not better,” put in Jerry,
“it is because they are not religious. You might as well say that our country's
laws are not good because some people break them. If a man gives way to his
temper, and speaks evil of his neighbor, and does not pay his debts, he is not
religious, I don't care how much he goes to church. If some men are shams and hung
bugs that does not make religion untrue.
Real Rel religion is the best and truest thing in the world, and the only thing
that can make a man really happy or make the world we live in any
better.” “If religion was good for anything,” said Jones, “it would prevent your
religious people from making us work on Sundays, as you know many of them do, and
that's why I say religion is nothing but a sham; why, if it was not for the church
and Chapel goers it would be hardly worthwhile our coming out on a Sunday.
But they have their privileges, as they call them, and I go without. I shall
expect them to answer for my soul, if I can't get a chance of saving
it.” Several of the men applauded this, till Jerry said: “That may sound well
enough, but it won't do; every man must look after his own soul; you can't lay it
down at another man's door like a foundling and expect him to take care of
it; and don't you see, if you are always sitting on your box waiting for a fair
they will say, 'If we don't take him someone else will, and he does not look for any
Sunday.' Of course, they don't go to the bottom of it, or they would see if they
never came for a cab it would be no use you standing there; but people don't
always like to go to the bottom of things; it may not be convenient to do it;
but if few Sunday drivers would all strike for a day of rest the thing would be
done.” “And what would all the good people do if they could not get to their
favorite preachers?” said Larry it is not for me to lay down plans
for other people,” said Jerry, “but if they can't walk so far they can
go to what is nearer; and if it should rain they can put on their macintoshes
as they do on a weekday If a thing is
right it can be done, and if it is wrong
it can be done without; and a good man
will find a way. And that is as true for us capmen as it is for the
churchgoers end of chapter